### Jorge García

jorest1994@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-garcia-45545790

Portfolio : <a href="https://jorest.github.io/">https://jorest.github.io/</a>

#### SUMMARY

Quality-oriented engineer, who likes to learn new things. I have experience working with multidisciplinary teams, with the ability to communicate and discuss new ideas. Experienced mainly as a programmer, and passionate about game design especially game mechanics.

Please feel free to check my technical skills and certificates on Linkedin.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Self-taught
- Creative
- Team player
- An analytical frame of mind
- knowledgeable in gaming trends

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelance Web Game Developer, Koji Social Mini Apps Platform 11/2019-Present

- Developing web-based games using javascript.
- The games are responsive and let the end-user change any asset.

# **IT Engineer**, Ericsson **03/2019-09/2019**

- Worked under the supervision of senior IT Engineers to implement, test, deploy, and support new features and fixes.
- I have worked on a telecom system, using a proprietary version of java.
- Worked both with Git and SVN.

### VR Developer, Optimus View 03/2018-10/2018

- Developed and tested VR applications using Unity, (C#) to showcase real-estate properties.
- Requirement gathering and customer liaising
- Optimized the frame per second, to be able to run the projects in lower spec machines.
- Worked with graphic designers, to make the features and aesthetics work well together.

#### Game Designer, Lion Works

03/2015- 10/2015

- Independent contractor as Game Designer for El Chavo Playbook Acalulpo
- Cooperated with programmers, artists, and management personal.
- Made fast changes on the game design, based on feedback, branding rules, or expert opinion.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Computer Science Engineering 01/2013- 12/2018

Universidad del Valle de Guatemala.

Academic achievements:

- distinguished student 2015
- distinguished student 2016
- Kept a Scholarship for five years

### Computer Science Engineering Abroad 02/2017

07/2016-

University of the Basque Country, Spain.

• Exchange student for a semester

### **CERTIFICATES**

- ETS TOEFL 102/120
- Linkedin Game Design Foundations (1,2,3)